e
all right welcome to this Mastermind and
Q&A for everybody to ask about
what this what I do to still kick my leg
up high into the sky at 70 and yes I
turned 70 last year in
August and of course you know this
filter in the camera that I can't do
anything about so that's why I look much
smoother than I actually am but you know
those are all the things but I feel
great in my body I don't have any aches
I don't have any pains I don't take any
pills I don't have any ills so those are
the things that I want you to ask me
about you know how do I do it and how do
I teach it and how can you maybe do it
by yourself or maybe you want to join um
a course that takes you through it so
that you really don't miss out on
actually making the changes that are
necessary to get there and I'll tell you
a little bit more about why so a little
just a short intro about me I'm of
course known as Professor Johanna Sophia
which I am I'm a professor and I am a
lot of other things so I wanted to tell
you just a quick rundown of my life
which is very unusual I have to say very
unusual many times I skipped what other
people go through in education because
because I could and you know not
everybody can and I'm not recommending
ending that anybody should but what
stayed constant is this pursuit of
wanting to help Humanity understand
better um be more
authentic love more I had the incredible
Fortune of being born to pacifist
parents my father's proudest achievement
in his younger years was that he got
through the second world war without
ever having to C carry a gun let alone
fire a gun as a as a first aid person
and he was only 16 when they caught him
in the mountains of the Alps where he
was hiding because he really did not
want to have to be a solder so that's
some of my background and my parents
both were Waldorf teachers so that's
based on the philosophy of Rudolph
Steiner and his approach was very much
that when we come into our own and are
our own being we don't really need
aggression and or revenge or um this
need for um oppression of others right
this need for being on top of others so
that is my Baseline just so you know so
it's this
humanitarianism
pacifism but also the dire
desire to help others come into this
come into your own as well I love it
when others come into their own so I had
a career of course at one point after
working with um special needs children
and adults in in a Camp Hill setting I
was only 17 but was respected as an
adult at the time and after that
I decided I wanted to go and mix and
mingle with the masses I called it so I
wanted to go into entertainment I
finished of course my school my high
school at the time I didn't
even
um and yeah actually I went straight
into teacher
training with waldor education but then
wanted to go into entertainment and did
so I had a eight-year career in singing
and acting and getting into movies and
teach specials Etc in fact I just got a
copy oh my God I should show
you I didn't plan this of the movie that
I'm one of the movies that I'm in and
this thing here is actually
me anyway
so
um then I met an African gentleman
and he became my first husband and I
moved to Zimbabwe and that's where I
learned how the world is run I learned
about the colonialism and how the entire
world was ruled by Europeans in so many
ways and exploited by Europeans and that
still holds true today and we have this
belief system that we think just because
we're the ones with the guns because
most of the rest of the world did not
have gunpowder and gun power right and
the will to kill and breaking treaties
and all of those things the Europeans
have always been very good at that
starting with the
Romans so I learned those things and the
Dynamics of warfare and patriarchy and
dominance and
exploitation and I'm feeling very
strongly about ever since that I want to
do something to teach others how to be
and again also how to teach other other
generations and other people around them
to be more in the space of building
something new rather than just
complaining about what's bad in the
world right first of course you have to
understand and then you have to build
something new and that also goes to
your your own excuse me your own body
you of course have to build your own
body into something stronger than what
you are given in a way by the lifestyle
that we've all been sold right and we've
been sold this lifestyle because of the
same powers that have sold us
colonialism and that's the way to go
right we've been sold to eat a lot of
white sugar white rice white flour um a
lot of an animal flesh that our bodies
are not really made to digest and all
these things um have impacted the world
over our state of being in our health
but there are enough pockets of people
who have different Lifestyles still even
today and show us that there is a
healthier way of living or confirm that
there is a healthier way of living um
and so that I'm also very interested in
I then from Zimbabwe my first husband
got a
scholarship to go to Columbia University
and to study film because he was already
in broadcasting in
Zimbabwe
and of course for me it was natural
after my acting career and in Zimbabwe I
had my own Studio I taught acting and
and um I'd been to to France to study
dance for a year as well while also
acting in movies so there's a lot of
stuff in my life that exposed me to a
lot of things that made it so that I
could understand that even with a very
weak body being born with a heart murmur
being born with very low blood pressure
which sounds good for all these people
who have very high blood pressure but if
it's too low you get very tired right
and you're probably iron deficient and
all these kind of issues that I had as a
young woman and you then are
particularly vulnerable to things that
cause infection such as dairy
consumption right I was always having
ear infections
and nose
throat um bronchitis all these issues
because I was so
susceptible and my parents didn't know
any better they thought Dairy was the
good part of animal products right so
they thought that was what what would
make us strong
um yeah so I
then also applied to Columbia University
there's a lot of other stuff in
between and unfortunately my marriage
didn't last and I went to Columbia
University and did three degrees in in
writing directing and producing film and
that's where my professorship comes from
I then taught at Colombia and at the
School of Visual Arts and at um Yale
University and City anyway a bunch of
others the colleges always as an Adjunct
professor because I did not want to be
tied down I loved traveling still do
between Europe and the
Americas and also Africa again and
again so yeah um became a filmmaker make
a C made a couple of small films that
won some awards but then I really really
wanted to have a family and film making
is not a secure income right you all
know that unless you are big and kind of
sell out in quotation marks to Hollywood
which was not my thing right I just
didn't it just never appealed to me but
it's not like I didn't also learn about
the corporate world um I got myself a
very well-paid job as a translator for
an international law firm
and um because I can translate five
languages so that worked very well and
that's where I learned how the weapons
industry and especially the
pharmaceutical industry Works in our
world yep lots of patents lots of um
tests and you know toxicity levels of
all these wonderful drugs that are so
making them so much
money so all of that
is there for kind of in my little in my
little suitcase of knowledge right about
how the world is run and how our health
is run by
these large pharmaceutical companies
that will do anything to make a buck
right and who's the best customer the
healthy person I'm not a good customer
for them
sorry
so I understand all of those mechanisms
that Prey Upon
Us and therefore was inclined even more
to create other avenues and help other
people see how these other avenues can
get you healthy even after being
diagnosed with all sorts of
things and retain your health
which is which is really the easy part
once you allow somebody to establish an
all over life style for yourselves and
many of my um clients have been able to
do that and it doesn't always look like
my
lifestyle but it can look
very interesting in different ways so
that we can establish a lifestyle that
keeps us the the way we want to feel the
way we want to be strong the way we also
want to be emotionally and mentally in a
good place and then I created of course
I studied also with many other people I
studied how to run an online coaching
business and for those of you who want
to
become active in that field I just this
morning spoke to one of my former
clients
in happy body course
who has developed her
own vegan High raw keto diet so you know
that keto works with low very low sugars
but um good fats and good um so in her
in her diet definitely no no animal fats
but good fats and good
um carbs that
are lots of greens and anyway she has
developed this whole system for herself
that makes her sound happy and glorious
and her clients um as well so I was
hoping she could be here to tell you
about her way of manifesting her own
business but she told me she has to look
after her very old and ailing mother so
who is not quite willing to change too
much of her lifestyle and that's
something of course that we also have to
contend with right every everybody has
their own threshold of how far they will
go in terms of
their um adjustments and we have to see
how well or not so
well they
can mentally and emotionally and
physically um withstand the changes
let's put it that way we then get we're
we're really creatures also of habit
once we establish a habit it becomes so
much easier to maintain a healthy
lifestyle um all right then I still
wanted if you want I'll tell you some
success stories just to give you
examples um so many such a wide range of
people I started working with um
teenagers when my kids were still young
teenagers and teenagers their parents
would say them to live with me for three
months at a time live with me and my
family and we would you know they would
have to adjust to our lifestyle and they
would do special things to and and work
with me to give
them the desire to live which is often a
problem with let's say 11 to 16 year
olds when they go through the physical
changes and the emotional changes of
having become
adults and anyway so I started working
with teenagers and some of them I'm
still in touch with um who are now
mothers and fathers and create their
Lifestyles for their families and then
um you know worked with professors who
are my clients and with um everybody in
between who some of whom created their
own businesses some of whom just wanted
to get super healthy for example I'm
thinking of as a um one of
those what's the word you know he's a
Mena member and a super brilliant person
and um but he's also very dark skinned
and
um and I'm saying
but
because often that creates a real
conflict especially in our Western world
where skin tone still ensues a lot of
discrimination and so he had worked with
with IBM as a very young man and then
was
ousted at 911 because he came from a
Muslim
background and you know and then he
became an artist and a filmmaker and he
got to a point where he was so sick and
kind of self-destructive
that he could not sleep at all anymore
he slept like in 20 minute segments if
he could at all and was highly diabetic
and kidney failure it's all these issues
that come together when um and severely
overweight so he came
to live in my house I actually had to go
pick him up because he couldn't travel
by himself anymore and within four days
he walked down the walk with me and
within 10 days he walked a mile slept
four hours at a time and and a good
night so that's how incredibly powerful
a full lifestyle change and a I work
with smoothies more than juices but a
smoothie cleanse that we all try to go
through in the beginning of class that's
how well that works and he's he's now
back in all kinds of businesses and how
to huge exhibition of his art in New
York City not so long ago is making
movies and yeah just is in full swing
has lost 85
pounds and um those are the stories you
know that work and of course after his
time intensively at my house we kept um
private coaching him through the changes
thereafter and yes that's a little more
expensive
but it's you know he will tell you I
saved his life so that's how much it can
be and it can also be just somebody who
wants to who already is like like
another client of mine Michael who had
um already was in the real estate
industry and wanted
to start however something that had to
do with nature so after exploring
creating a camp for children because
those were good memories of his he
decided on a glamping business cuz he
had a piece of land so he then um yeah
learned and explored what that entails
went to a couple of glamping sites and
now he has his own glamping
business so that's just to show you wide
range of things that can happen another
person completed her her novel her book
in my class and so there's all these
possibilities and because I have very
small classes that's why that can work
with very individual
issues
so I would love to get the first
questions because probably some of the
things that I was was going to tell you
next about what's involved in in really
getting yourself into the new system
even if you don't take the class even if
if you do it by yourself um is probably
what your questions are anybody want to
start did you take note of the question
that you want to
ask yes I was wondering um when the
smoothie cleanse
happens do you have dates for it yet or
can you give us an idea when it might be
um yeah the the class does the does the
smoothie cleanse a week in into the
class so the first week is more about we
all establish our goals we have our
strategy calls that are one-on-one calls
everybody gets their one-on-one call so
that we can then introduce to each other
what we what we want to
pursue is another Machu okay um and then
the the second or the third week it
depends a little bit on how many people
we how much time we need for everybody
to present their goals right and then
the smoothie cleanse is a five to S day
um cleanse period of time um where we do
all smoothies the first three days
smoothies plus a salad the next two days
but salad of course all just raw greens
and there can be some fruit in there
there too um and then some people want
to extend it to seven days but that's
optional so that's that's how we start
out
because my understanding is that we need
to start with
a strong physical body right into
anything so I want us to get at least
the it's also in my evolved system
it's it's the second um Step verify the
science I.E you know we learn about how
the biology actually operates which our
chemical industry does not tell us how
biology really works how we need to feed
our cell tissue so that it can renew
itself Etc so we research about that and
we demonstrate by experiencing how it
works we
experience the physical mental emotional
changes that happen when you allow
yourself to cleanse like that
um it's it's kind of it's the entry
into oh it's somebody's phone I guess
maybe even mine I thought I had turned
it all the way off could be that it's
vibrating yeah it is sorry about that um
so yeah Machu do you want to show
yourself can you hear me
okay never mind if you just want to want
to watch that's fine too um I just of
course you know I always like people to
introduce
themselves so yeah so once we have this
cleansing
experience it is so much easier than get
to the next stage that we slowly
approach and it takes a little while
to work through and that's the turn your
traumas into tool stage because of
course we all have
traumata traumas from the traumas from
our childhood from our life experience
maybe even from our last separation from
a partner or a parent died Etc so we all
have things that sort
of
um D us down in a way because
yeah maybe we feel co-responsible for
what happened to somebody or we all
these issues that we
have and maybe we feel we were wronged
by others or by the world and things
happened to us that we had
no responsibility in so all these issues
become easier
to Grapple with and work through
um after the physical
cleanse it's just we become more at ease
with
ourselves when our body feels
better and like I like I explained with
Ali this bodily feeling better is really
fast in most cases I yeah have rarely
experience that somebody does not quite
get there it happens um that there's a
lot more
[Music]
ongoing
conflict in our inner life right and it
could be also in our outer life we know
when we're under
stress under Financial stress under job
stress Etc all those things of course
impact our well-being our health
physically and
mentally um so yeah does that answer
your question and is it very
unsatisfactory that I can't put it put a
pin into whether it's the second or
third week
Hillary no that's okay and was there
another um I haven't looked at my notes
in a in a little while was there another
chunk of time too where we were doing
something together that is useful to
know we're always doing something
together I know there was something else
there was but there was a particular
project like the cleanse project um I
thought there was a yeah there's also
after the after the initial I I encourag
the 21 days on Raw so you then you then
still continue for 21 days to to eat but
eat various foods and preferably the
majority
raw because that again builds
more more cell tissue and you need the
replenishment of nutrients of real
nutrients
to get your cell tissue replication
working well because it biology really
boils down
to can our body rebuild
itself after the damage that has been
done right and I always say look when
you cut yourself that wound is trying
it's darn us to grow back together it's
never that it tries to grow further
apart and get worse right only if you
really do a bad job um will it not heal
itself it will the body itself wants to
heal itself it's made that way and it's
not just in human bodies but the tree if
you cut into it you know will grow back
together we'll have a little scar
everything in nature wants to heal
itself if at all
possible I was at one point I was
showing
that I had cut a mango top off and I
thought oh this is still too green right
and I put the top back on and left it
lying there and it grew back together
you could see the fibers hooking back
into each other so that's how much life
wants to heal itself right um and yes of
course I butchered the mango when it was
ripe anyway because I wanted to eat it
yeah but I of course we all have our
philosophies as to why eating plants is
of course especially fruits is the thing
to to do and greens and fruits and of
course nuts are the core of fruits so
they really are part of the fruit in so
many
ways
um yeah so that's why this the the 21
days on Raw is
another period that we try to do as best
we can not everybody does it some people
feel that they're good with mostly
cooked and just a little raw but mostly
because of that experience of the five
days on smoothies and how good you feel
how you wake up in the morning and you
well rested and it's just hard to beat
that feeling with any other
diet so it kind kind of happens that way
and then we do other things together
where everybody for example where
everybody
finds
um 10 experts that they would like to
talk to or interview if you know if
you're build especially if you're
building a business or if you just want
to follow them also because I'm not the
only
person knowledgeable of stuff right I
have talked to countless
experts in the field of health and
healing the planet and sustainability
and I've had I didn't mention that I've
had a Solar Company for a minute so I
learned a lot about alternative energies
and of course they're much better
energies even than solar energy that we
could harness but they're not
profitable so all these things and
depending on what we're
pursuing can
be um done as a group where everybody
does their thing but we're doing
something
similar right like everybody then
presents their 10 experts to the group
and tells us
why um they've learned something from
them right or why they want to if they
want to build an online business why
they want to interview them and that
that is then set up so that everybody
can and that creates what is called a
tribe or lead production so that you
have people who will want to work with
you similarly to how you guys found me
right Ed wodinsky for example has
followed me for for a few years now
right Ed right yeah and sometimes we've
talked and then you found I believe you
found Zen right
meditation uh meditation yeah
yeah and that has given you what you
needed right right so that's also uh I I
applaud that when you find your Avenue
to to um feel that you're in the right
place and in the right
space so if you want tell me each a
little bit how what your vision is for
the next 12 months even if you're not in
the
class yeah go ahead
Marcia oh you you muted click the click
the little
microphone
right I kind of fell into this session
this morning a little bit by
accident I was previously already on a
zoom which just finished and your
information came up I have been
receiving um emails but I didn't really
pursue a relationship with you what I
would first like to say is that I have
caregivers come to me every day and I am
scheduled to have a visit from a
caregiver in a little while so if I
suddenly
disappear that's why that is
but this um I think somehow it's like a
Divine appointment because I'm very
interested in your life and this topic
I'm very sick at the moment with
diabetes yes and I informed my doctor
wanted to do a detox because I have also
done some work it's a study and then
work as a therapist in what they call an
alternative um method of muscle and
connective tissue therapy and so but my
doctor informed me that it would be very
very dangerous oh yes yes yes I'm
sorry I have learned also that this is
It's not that it's their stock answer
but it's not part of their training so
they don't like to get into it and we've
worked out a sort of a compromise where
I did smoothies and
juices but my blood sugars at the moment
are quite High I recently had um a
TIA yeah and the medical people sent me
back from hospital with a lot of
medication and I told the doctor I
really didn't want to take it and if I
had my choice I'd like to sack her
yes um Marcia where are you sitting in
which where are you calling from which
country New Zealand you are also in New
Zealand that's too funny do you know
each other
Seline that is too funny Selena is also
in New Zealand oh really
whereabouts unmute yourself
Seline we can't hear
you
hit the little microphone that is too
funny so Marcia I'm going to send you a
movie right away a documentary it's
called simply raw reversing diabetes in
30 days yes so I also
following um Shane
Sterling I don't know Shane Sterling but
I will look is that a he or
she it is a a male mhm and he has um ra
raw
vegan Heroes and raw vegan
rising and
but the medical people I'm working with
have reduced my I'm sorry I'm speaking
this quickly because I may have to leave
you shortly oh you're you're very
welcome
um and they have reduced my medication
which I'm pleased about but my blood
sugars are quite High which I'm not
pleased to and I have been
going a bit more L than I was
before
um and so when I heard what your topic
was I I'm into it because it sparked my
interest yes so um I would like
to um pursue this relationship with you
uhia do me a favor put your email in the
chat before you have to
go I am not very tax savy so I don't
know where to oh I see you don't see
where the chat is um where did you find
me on social media or on an email now
I've lost you all together because I've
gone back to the zoom screen and I have
a oh I'm I'm there you go to the bottom
of your screen say it out loud you could
just say she could just say it out loud
and you can write it down yes just say
your email yes it is
mia. skilbeck
gmail.com is skill or skillbeck
sko Beck s
i k i l only one l oh I see b e c k at
gmail.com got it and Marcy is spelled
how m a r c i a yeah I I see it on the
screen I see her name on the screen tell
me where Seline is
please
hello I'm gonna connect you with Seline
also Ruby Bay
Nelson on the south island oh yes yes I
have been there I'm in the North Island
in
Ty all right
okay I can't I can't find you again now
I'm still in the zoom screen um Marcia
go to the bottom of your screen and see
the little
ZM for Zoom a little like an an icon and
click click on that then the screen
should open back
up on the bottom of your
screen there I I got you got you yes I
got you very good all right well you
know we all start somewhere sometimes
mysteriously somewhere
right and so I will get in touch with
you no matter what so that that we can
figure out whether we can work together
beautiful it would be great if if you
also hook up with Seline and you're both
in the same I've got your email I'll
contact you as
well yeah oh that's lovely lovely I look
forward to that yeah another thing yeah
go
ahead yeah my caregiver sometimes is a
bit flexible in the timing so I wanted
to speak first to explain all of that I
may just disappear from your meeting but
it doesn't mean lack of Interest I may
just have to goote I got you I got you
which is wonderful all right
so
um it's always like I said it's always
miraculous how we meet each other I
can't even remember or I do remember how
I met because we were talking about him
Ali I met Ali through a colleague of
mine who is a
screenwriting coach and had worked with
Ali on a movie so you know sometimes
it's so mysteriously backwards Howe yes
and my interest to you to to also is
from the age of four I was a dancer and
I enjoyed singing too yes and I
musically I play the keyboard and the
piano
accordion and so I guess in that way I
was drawn to you when you explained your
previous background history yes anyway I
don't want to take up time one more one
more thing for you Marcia we have a jazz
singer in this class she already is
subscribed and she I just talked to her
this morning she wants to get back into
singing and she knows all these jazz
songs and she has worked with me a
little bit before and you know I I still
teach people particular singing
exercises to open up the the resonances
in the head so that you don't sing like
oh but you sing
like so you know and and the other thing
is when you do these exercises and you
eat the way I eat you don't become an
old lady voice
like you
know you know the old ladies in the
choir when they're all
like yes yes well speaking of that I am
I am coming up shortly to 81 and a lot
of people have written me off and I am
resisting that because um I told someone
the other day I was planning not to die
and she said well good luck with
that well you know you can give yourself
another couple Decades of beautiful
existence you
know and in that context I like to tell
people the story that um one morning
when I was
66 I woke up and I said to
myself oh my God I have 30 more years to
live what did I do in the last 30 years
it was so
much and in 30 years I could do so much
more and that same day I was driving and
listening to a radio
show and there was
this this um Tango Daner was described
as coming to the Australian not
Australian to the um
Argentinian World Tango Festival and
getting all the press and guess how old
he was
99 whoa well done Scottish tango dancers
from Scotland flew to Argentina to
participate in the world Tango
whatever um competition celebration and
all of that so I said who am I to say
that I'm only gonna be 96
right so that that's my experience with
you know planning the future but yeah a
lot can be I mean what matters more is
how we live I
feel yes I'm almost like well if
something happened tomorrow and I would
not be here anymore I'd be fine with it
because I lived every day of my life
with great
intensity great love for life and to the
best ability and there will be days
where we feel like we fail completely
that's just power for the course I just
did a whole podcast on
failure okay I'mma let I'mma let
Marcia's topic go let's have some other
questions Ed come on we want a question
from you I want a question from
[Music]
you have you found a new place to live
yeah a beautiful little house that I'm
buying yeah good yeah yeah yeah with
with a deck with a great view across the
entire Valley especially in the winter
but even in the summer there's like a
like what you call it a corridor through
the trees where you can see the entire
Valley and I like that a lot
yes
yeah it's going to be not this huge open
space big space that I have here but
it's that beautiful deck instead and it
also has a great um studio in the
basement that is very large so yeah I'm
I'm happy to have found a place that I'm
actually in the process of buying oh
good yeah yeah how is you're you're
you're in Canada still right
yeah yeah living with the repressive
government here where the price of goods
here is probably two to three times the
price of yours and our dollar is like
40% less so it makes everything very
expensive here yeah because of the
carbon tax yes that we have that you
don't have yeah and they're raising it
again April the 1 another 23%
whoa yeah it's people
here are are going bankrupt there's the
food banks have had record number of uh
usages you know is it's just it's just
incredible here the the economic dire
situation in our country now so
yeah yeah so you you you have to figure
out a way to be at least on the fringes
of the upper classes right in order to
even survive yeah yeah yeah so but if
you want to talk to me more about how
you could use your skills of a lifetime
to be in those fringes and make extra
money I'm happy to talk to you about the
possibilities that I can see I know that
it's tougher in Canada even than in the
United States but yeah it's possible
here and I know it's possible there too
because
yeah you got just got to get yourself to
the other side of rather the provider
than the recipient of um all the help
systems that are however also in place
you
know great y right like I mean if you
think of the food system and the food
banks you have to be on the side where
you're working with the people providing
the food so that you have a secure extra
income to
your I think you have a very small
retirement um Social Security type
income right yep yeah you had told me
how how little it is and I was very
shocked so I know yeah it's it's pitiful
here yeah yeah so but again you know
there are ways to get to that other side
of the of the let's call it the game
because it is a a terrible game that
we're all stuck in and we have to know
we have to learn how to play the game so
that we can survive and still do good by
ourselves and to others it's possible Y
and there's so and the other thing is Ed
that so many people around the world are
working on exactly that like take in
Great Britain George Galloway has just
won his district election and is become
becoming a very important person in in
Parliament
right judge Galloway is um I don't know
whether you follow International
politics is a man who has literally as a
Young Man fought with the um in South
Africa for Black
Liberation in the 80s you know that
South Africa
became free of a parde theoretically and
and then practically with Nelson
everybody is familiar with Nelson
Mandela right
that's right yeah yeah you all familiar
with Nelson Mandela oh yeah yep so
George Gallow was helping the Nelson
Mandela people and Nelson Mandela
himself to get to the point of
being elected president so and he's but
as a British citizen he you know many
International people did help down there
so he's got into parliament in Great
Britain that means a lot it means that
the mindset of people is Shifting you
know already we because now we're at a
point where not just the African
continent and the Asian continent and
the Latin American continent are
exploited now we are all
exploited as well right we're feeling it
we the good old white folks feel
suddenly that we're being exploited as
well yeah with the last with the
last um category of people right we we
considered ourselves like Untouchable in
a in a certain way um I certainly
can you know it hit me hard when I moved
to Africa and really learned how the
world
works so yeah now we are on the
receiving end of the exploitation as
well like you said you know everything
is taken from you so that you will fall
into the category of you will own
nothing but you will be happy supposedly
right because we medicate you into
Oblivion yeah the new world economic
Forum agenda yeah exactly so we have to
be clever enough to find the people with
whom we can collaborate on these new
models and also clever enough to be on
those fringes of the wealthy so that we
can have an income that allows us to
collaborate with others you know because
it will
entail traveling or meeting with others
and doing things together that are like
the trucker Convoy you know even though
that wasn't much of a philosophical
thing it was a very important movement
right that showed the world that people
who are ignored can make a show for it
and yes they were not as successful as
we all would have want them to wanted
them to be but they got it done and got
the world
attention yeah so
yeah um Hillary do you have any more
questions um I probably do but off the
top of my
head um
it's hard to think I've just been kind
of absorbing I think I'll um need to go
back to the papers you know description
you sent me and then um email you yeah
we'll do so then then let me go through
the different points that are important
to establish also what I was just
discussing with Ed you know that finding
that middle ground where you're not
betraying Yourself by um falling
into the other side you
know to me when I when I kind of went
corporate in quotation marks by working
for this international law firm and you
know our clients were Bayer and fizer
and um lucky Martin and you know those
were our clients so you can understand
what kind of insights I had into the
mechanisms of those worlds right when
you are working for those people
if you are working with an understanding
of I am not corruptible but I am here to
analyze how things work right and of
course I had to perform the best I could
perform had the best accolades in that
performance but it gave me an
opportunity an ed that goes for you too
because you worked in the oil industry
right yeah yeah so you know when we use
that experience that we have for the
understanding of the mechanics of how
they do it right then it becomes an
asset and then we become not the victims
but the
knowledgeablevids
of doing things differently because we
have a basis of
understanding um so yeah in the class we
go from the what we discussed the the
smoothies the 21 days on Raw the mental
um turn your traumas into tools and that
has to do
with I trust that everything we have
experienced the The Good the Bad and the
Ugly can be helping us to feel stronger
not only because we survived but also
because
we I have to adjust the lighting here
yeah but also because we
have accumulated all that
knowledge and therefore
have
gained understanding of how why people
are so sick and if we especially or why
people are so feeling so down because
they've had all this trauma and we can
say yeah that's part of my life I
can use that if you if you want as power
of food it makes me more strong rather
than weakens me yes
Hillary um the the two components the um
healing our bodies and then figuring out
our life's work and setting that up um
can we determine how much of each we do
because I'm I'm in a mode now I mean
I've been like workaholic in the past
and um I now I'm dealing with the cancer
and I just I'm in a self-care mode now
and yes I'm getting business ideas and
setting up things and trying to finish
up old projects um but I want to do the
business stuff just like on the side at
my own pace I don't want to pressure
myself at all because I'm kind of in the
opposite mode of just being in healing
is that will that fit with what we're
doing absolutely Ely yes yes yes
originally the class was only for that
for self-healing self-empowering
creating a new lifestyle and really
becoming at home in that new lifestyle
and in that new body and yes your body
will
heal great and it takes different
amounts of time I when I describe Ali it
was a very short time because he's such
a Powerhouse also to overcome all these
issues
for other people it takes the whole year
to get to that equilibrium of okay now
I'm good with
myself and yeah no absolutely yes the
short answer is absolutely yes that's
how I originally designed the class and
then there were many people who said
okay now I also want to do something
like what you do or I also want to you
know and right and then it became the
certified coach um Avenue that you can
also pursue where you get your
certificate and it it it I challenge you
of course for the certificate you have
to write at the end you write a 20page
paper and you know you you really know I
have a coaching certificate I just I
know you do myself and set up and get
going I I got you so no absolutely you
and your body can be the
only
purpose
throughout okay yeah
and you will find that the others will
be very supportive of that because of
course as we age we all have to that's
why it's still called the super happy
body class because without a super happy
body you cannot possibly do what you
want to do in life
effectively
right right yeah I mean yes there are
some examples of like Stephen Hawk
Hawkins was it um who um of course did
not have a functioning body and was just
using his
brain and still imagine if he would
have allowed himself to strengthen that
body first how much more he could have
done you know to me the argument always
goes both
ways yeah it certainly didn't enable him
more to be sick
so
yeah
um
good Marcia you still with us or are you
frozen you still with
us okay um so sorry I muted myself again
but yes I am still with you can you not
see me my screen has gone
funny oh your screen has gone funny
again I can only see the top of head
like this oh
yes you have to do this to let me know
your your breathing okay so the next um
element is that we find new connections
to society by finding by either
reconnecting with with um family members
that we've been distant to by forgiving
ourselves and it's kind of a whole
oponopono experience as well as if
you're familiar with that mod
do you need yeah and it's also um that
we find groups who are going through
similar things or that we're interested
in and that we can join whether they're
online or in phys better is physical um
I'm sure there are
um healthy healing from cancer groups
you know where you
can so so it's it's connecting with the
world is is another stage but that's
after we have connected with ourselves
have found also what I left out is the
fitness modality that we want to pursue
some people will do yoga others will do
Pilates others will just do walking
others will do some mild exercises at
home there's so many different ways but
moving is very much part of the healing
process as
well so we just lost Marcia
good so I'm just going through the rest
of the
steps and then comes the point at which
we we design the structure for either
our lifestyle so that there's a baseline
again from which we can work or for our
for our business even if it's a sidekick
business if you have a a structure and a
modality like every week I'm going to do
one client one talk or something like
that right um that's all good and there
are other ways of earning money on the
side for both Ed and and Hillary it
doesn't have to be coaching you know
there are many other modalities by which
we can earn extra income and that
exposes us to another part of the world
that we feel good participating in right
it can be
um I was just this morning talking to
somebody also you know it could be
working in a soup kitchen it could be
working in um anything that gives us a
sense of or people's people's churches
or it it could be all kinds of things
that gives us a sense of
purpose in addition to Healing ourselves
and that creates income I mean some
people have enough of a trust fund that
they can just do voluntary work I'm not
one of those lucky ones but
so right neither I know neither are you
to
so um so yeah that's part of the next
stage is connecting with the world in
various ways and you know again we put
out a task to everybody okay who are the
three people that you connected with or
organizations and people bring um that
back to the group and tell us about what
um they experienced and why they
connected with that group or that
individual and then lastly I wanted to
emphasize that you can create lifelong
friendships in these small groups I am
still in touch with some of my business
colleagues from when I first learned
online business in 2013 14 15 and we
have and and there in in in England and
actually one is in New Zealand and
Australia in Canada and all over the us
so I have all these virtual friends who
are and I'm I'm seeing the kind of
businesses that they built right and we
support each other we tell each other
that we like what they're posting and so
forth um it's just a
wonderful way of knowing that I'm not
alone in struggling as an as an
entrepreneur if that's what you're
pursuing or or as a human being for that
matter or with your health so there's
this connectivity that you build in
these classes and hopefully you will
stay in touch with each other and meet
some of the previous clients and or
future clients and so forth so that's
that's the the additional that's the
value added kind of thing to being in a
class that you feel
you've created a a family of sorts for
yourself that you now belong
to yeah I've met enormously wonderful
people you know I've I've traveled to
places where former clients of M are and
have resided in their homes in Florida
or in in in Germany or in you know and
it's it's just a beautiful thing that
um that there is a human bond in
addition
to to the learning process that we
create because you see I come from and I
want this for everybody who's also might
be listening to this at a later time I
come from a philosophy where we need to
overcome competition and transition to
contribution as the principle that
drives Us in all our
interactions so not competing with
anybody for business or something I'm
contributing my share and I'm
acknowledging other people's
contributions and every contribution
matters and is a beautiful
thing so in that
sense um I also want to encourage you to
find your way to contribute to the
family of humanity and to all these
smaller and larger forms of families who
are off that
mindset it's a beautiful thing and it's
everywhere in the world I find that that
is
growing that the understanding being and
I don't know whether you've come across
it too the two of you um that people are
moving away from elbow competition
right and putting other people down
because they feel like like they need to
be on top it still exists
but but we can find lots and lots
of moving
toward teamwork collaboration Mutual
enhancement rather
than
Mutual destruction which you know is is
sad in the end when you think about
it all right
sense yeah yeah all right Ed let's let's
set up um A Time For Us by i' set it up
by email to to explore a little bit what
else you can do to enhance your income
situation because yes I mean that's
that's just sad you know you've worked
all your life in an industry that makes
billions and billions not
trillions I can't hear
yeah yeah so and why shouldn't you
have a good life right after all that
work right y so yeah all right good and
Hillary you're gonna talk to Linda right
yes she's actually expecting your call
and um great thank you for that
yeah and
and I shall see you on Tuesday unless
you want to have your strategy call
before which we can also
said yeah and it's it's an interesting
class because it ranges in age
from okay he just told me he's 29 so
he's not not I thought he was in his
younger 20s but you know two almost 80
or like if if of course if Marcia joins
the class we're looking at
80 she looks how many people do you have
so far H how many people are in the
class so far it looks like seven could
be less could be because not everybody
has put their money where their mouth is
right so that's always the that's always
the thing and I know that for Ed that's
also a big thing but maybe we can find a
solution there too all
right then with this I shall close out
our our Mastermind and hope that you all
learn some things have been triggered to
think about your own life and what
matters in your own life and
have yeah if you want to connect with me
you know how to connect with me just if
you don't have my email address it's
johanah johannas foods.com just Google
Prof Johanna Sophia or Professor Johanna
sopia and you will find my websites and
my contact info and this is for all the
people who see this at a later time on
my online Channel on YouTube where this
is going to go it's easy to find me by
Googling not Johanna sopia that will
bring up all kinds of other people
Professor Johanna
Sophia so there I'm still Rarity among
the professors with the last name Sophia
or with a online name you know um but it
is my real name
so good I look forward to seeing you
wherever I see you next or hear from you
or read from you and I'm saying goodbye
thank you for being
here
ciao You by bye bye